<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Process Manager Virtual DOS Machine (VDM) support functions on GeoB99 Website</title><link>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/vdm/</link><description>Recent content in Process Manager Virtual DOS Machine (VDM) support functions on GeoB99 Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/vdm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PspDeleteVdmObjects</title><link>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/vdm/pspdeletevdmobjects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/vdm/pspdeletevdmobjects/</guid><description>Description Deletes Virtual DOS Machine (DOS) objects. The function is called in a process deletion scenario (called by PspDeleteProcess).
Internals &amp;amp; Parameters VOID NTAPI PspDeleteVdmObjects( IN PEPROCESS Process) Process is a pointer to a Executive process (EPROCESS). The function internally frees the VdmObjects member of the EPROCESS structure and deletes the Executive resource from the system&amp;rsquo;s resources list. Besides that, the function also deallocates the memory pool block within the memory space of the Virtual DOS Machine (VDM) objects.</description></item><item><title>PspVdmInitialize</title><link>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/vdm/pspvdminitialize/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/vdm/pspvdminitialize/</guid><description>Description Initializes the Virtual DOS Machine (DOS) in boot phase.
Internals &amp;amp; Parameters NTSTATUS NTAPI PspVdmInitialize(VOID) The function takes no parameters, it merely initializes the VDM during boot phase specifically during process manager initialization procedure &amp;ndash; first phase (PspInitPhase0). PspInitPhase0 is invoked by PsInitSystem, the completion of the 1st phase leads with the preparation for the 2nd phase initialization. PspVdmInitialize returns a NTSTATUS value, STATUS_SUCCESS respectively. The function invokes the Executive to add the VDM resource in the system resources list which in turn the kernel is responsible for managing such resource for whatever purpose in the context of VDM.</description></item></channel></rss>