<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Process Manager Local Descriptor Table support functions on GeoB99 Website</title><link>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/ldt/</link><description>Recent content in Process Manager Local Descriptor Table support functions on GeoB99 Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/ldt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PspDeleteLdt (Local Descriptor Table)</title><link>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/ldt/pspdeleteldt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/ldt/pspdeleteldt/</guid><description>Description Deletes the Local Descriptor Table (LDT) resources previously created by PspCreateLdt.
Internals &amp;amp; Parameters VOID NTAPI PspDeleteLdt( IN PEPROCESS Process) Process is a pointer to a Executive process (EPROCESS). The function gathers the non-paged pool quota of the process and deallocates the memory pool block within the memory space. The aforementioned memory pool is created by PspCreateLdt during the call of ExAllocatePoolWithTag function. The tag named for such pool memory is dLsP.</description></item><item><title>PspLdtInitialize</title><link>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/ldt/pspldtinitialize/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/ldt/pspldtinitialize/</guid><description>Description Initialises the Local Descriptor Table (LDT) during the early boot phase (Phase 0).
Internals &amp;amp; Parameters VOID NTAPI PspLdtInitialize(VOID) The function takes no arguments. What does it simply do is to initialise a mutant object specifically in the context of the LDT realm. Internally such mutant object (or mutex) is named as LdtMutex. The initialisation of such LDT mutex object is done at the early boot phase of Windows, in PspInitPhase0 function which is responsible for Process Manager kernel subsystem initialisation.</description></item><item><title>PspQueryLtdInformation</title><link>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/ldt/pspqueryltdinformation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/ldt/pspqueryltdinformation/</guid><description>Description This function queries the local descriptor table (LDT) information of a specific process.
Internals &amp;amp; Parameters This function takes a number of 4 parameters, it is unknown the nature of the said parameters and what are they. However it is noted that this function returns a value of NTSTATUS. An example of NTSTATUS values returned by this function are STATUS_INFO_LENGTH_MISMATCH, STATUS_INVALID_LDT_SIZE and STATUS_INVALID_LDT_OFFSET.
Called Functions _SEH_prolog KeWaitForSingleObject KeReleaseMutex _SEH_epilog</description></item><item><title>PspSetLdtInformation</title><link>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/ldt/pspsetldtinformation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/ldt/pspsetldtinformation/</guid><description>Description Sets the LDT information to a specific process given the process executive.
Internals &amp;amp; Parameters NTSTATUS NTAPI PspSetLdtInformation( IN PEPROCESS Process, IN PROCESS\_LDT\_INFORMATION LdtInformation, IN ULONG InformationLength) Process is a pointer to a EPROCESS structure, the executive process. LdtInformation contains information about Local Descriptor Table (LDT) entries. InformationLength is the size length, in bytes, of the second parameter which is LdtInformation. The function returns a NTSTATUS value, that is, STATUS_SUCCESS if the operation completed successfully or STATUS_ACCESS_VIOLATION if a specific address is invalid or not allowable for read/write that the caller tried to access it.</description></item><item><title>PspSetLdtSize</title><link>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/ldt/pspsetldtsize/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigwait.github.io/GeoB99.github.io/pages/doc/ntoskrnl/ps/ldt/pspsetldtsize/</guid><description>Description Sets the Local Descriptor Table (LDT) size of a Executive process object.
Internals &amp;amp; Parameters NTSTATUS NTAPI PspSetLdtSize( IN PEPROCESS Process, IN PROCESS\_LDT\_SIZE LdtSize, IN ULONG InformationLength) Process is a pointer to a Executive process (EPROCESS). LdtSize is the Local Descriptor Table (LDT) size pointed by its particular structure &amp;ndash; PROCESS_LDT_SIZE. InformationLength is the length size, in bytes, pointed by LdtSize parameter. The function is internally called by NtSetInformationProess() when ProcessLdtSize information class is invoked.</description></item></channel></rss>